Wesley Tansey

wes.tansey@gmail.com http://cs.utexas.edu/~tansey

(804)-867-5306 5207 Wayborne Hill Dr., Austin, TX

Research Statement

I'm a PhD student in the Neural Networks Research Group at UT Austin. My main research interests are machine learning and medical applications, particularly how we can use big data to discover and recommend better treatments for patients with chronic illness. I spend most of my days working on algorithms to create personalized, adaptive treatments from patient health logs. If successful, these techniques may be able to improve the lives of millions of people living with chronic disease, as well as making substantial advances in the field of reinforcement learning.

I am passionate about taking my research into the real world and using machine learning to make people healthier and happier. Towards this goal, I am currently collaborating with companies enabling people to track various aspects of their health. I am currently collaborating with multiple startups, focusing on everything from Crohn's disease to obesity, with the goal of empowering their users to improve their health and fitness through personalized recommendations.

Education

$2011\mathrm{-Present}$	Pursuing PhD in Computer Science, University of Texas at Austin
	Graduate Coursework:
	Graphical Models, Neural Networks, Bayesian Statistical Methods,,
	Natural Language Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Statistical Modeling II,
	MCMC Methods, Mathematical Logic, Computer Security, Programming Languages
2006-2008	MS in Computer Science, Virginia Tech
	GPA 3.81
2003-2006	BS in Computer Science, Virginia Tech
	GPA 3.55

Select P

Publications	
2012	W. Tansey, E. Feasley, and R. Miikkulainen. Accelerating evolution via egalitarian social learning. In <i>Proceedings of the Fourteenth International Conference on Genetic and Evolutionary Computation Conference (GECCO 2012)</i> , pages 919–926. ACM, 2012
2012	R. Miikkulainen, E. Feasley, L. Johnson, I. Karpov, P. Rajagopalan, A. Rawal, and W. Tansey. Multiagent learning through neuroevolution. <i>Advances in Computational Intelligence</i> , pages 24–46, 2012
2008	W. Tansey and E. Tilevich. Annotation refactoring: inferring upgrade transformations for legacy applications. In <i>Proceedings of the 23rd ACM SIGPLAN Conference on Object-Oriented Programming Systems, Languages, and Applications (OOPSLA 2008)</i> , volume 43, pages 295–312. ACM, 2008
2008	W. Tansey and E. Tilevich. Efficient automated marshaling of C++ data structures for MPI applications. In <i>Proceedings of the 2008 IEEE International Symposium on Parallel and Distributed Processing (IPDPS 2008)</i> , pages 1–12. IEEE, 2008

Work Experience

Currently | PhD Student, UT Austin

In the Neural Networks group led by Risto Miikkulainen

Researching hierarchical Bayesian reinforcement learning for adaptive treatment discovery for patients with chronic illness. Co-wrote grant that earned funding from the NSF's BEACON Center.

2014 | Data Science Intern, MyFitnessPal

Diet and fitness recommender systems research.

Coming in Summer 2014. :)

2013 Software Engineering Intern, Google

Researched how to improve automated auction bidding.

Implemented and evaluated alternative bidding strategy experiments on massive datasets.

2011-2014 Teaching Assistant, Computer Science Department, UT Austin

Participated in developing course materials for hundreds of students.

Helped setup up competition for AI MOOC class taught by Peter Norvig. Directly managed team of four undergrad researchers.

2011-2012 Co-founder, Curvio Inc.

Built, launched, and iterated a consumer web startup.

Organically grew site to 2k uniques/day. Managed a team of 12 remote contractors and hundreds of turkers.

2010 | Co-founder, EffectCheck (Effect Technologies Inc.)

Created novel machine learning algorithms for sentiment analysis.

Worked all areas of the business: front-end, back-end, sales, partnerships, and marketing.

2010-2011 | Machine Learning Contractor, Natural Selection Financial

Researched adaptive machine learning models for quantitative finance.

Developed algorithms that explore huge data sets and discover exploitable patterns in market prices.

2008-2010 Res

Research Associate, Lincoln Vale Adaptive Strategies (Hedge Fund)

Researched and implemented machine learning algorithms for automated trading.

Developed 20+ real-world trading algorithms, with millions of dollars wagered on their predictions every day.

Skills

Python, Ruby, R, C#, C/C++, Java, HTML, CSS, and Javascript Technical writing, team leadership, startups, statistical modeling Building systems to collect, clean, analyze, and learn from data

Awards and Miscellanea

Garg Fellowship for Research with Real-World Impact

Recipient of NSF Beacon Grant

NSF Graduate Research Fellowship Program, Honorable Mention in Machine Learning

Outstanding Graduate Student Award, Virginia Tech

Finished the San Diego Rock'n'Rock Marathon in 5:38:11

Projects available on my website: http://cs.utexas.edu/~tansey